Contact

karinw3095@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/karin-frodin-white-rn-mba-aa9226ba (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare
Healthcare Management
Nursing Management

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Registered Nurse RN Registered Nurse RN

Karin Frodin White, RN MBA

Chief Nursing Officer CNO at Central Montana Medical Center Lewistown, Montana

Summary

I have 30+ years of diverse experience in Nursing, Nursing Management, Public Health, Epidemiology, Disaster Preparedness, Infection Prevention, Quality Improvement/Assurance, Employee Health, Laboratory Science and Project Management. I navigate easily in one or many disciplines, sometimes wearing one or many hats as the need arises. My passion is bridging disciplines into a cohesive team approach to healthcare.

Experience

Central Montana Medical Center Chief Nursing Officer CNO June 2017 - Present (3 years 2 months) Lewistown, Montana

Provide leadership, engaging caregivers in providing safe, evidenced based, quality care through a teamwork approach. We are passionate about our patients who have entrusted us with their care. Executive Team Member.

Blue Mountain Hospital District Chief Clinical and Nursing Officer CCO/CNO July 2015 - June 2017 (2 years) John Day, Oregon

25 bed Critical Accces Hospital. 275 employees

Oversee all nursing services, ancillary services and clinical operations. Serve as Executive team member.

Blue Mountain Hospital in John Day, Oregon Chief Clinical Officer CCO/Interim Chief Executive Officer CEO July 2015 - June 2016 (1 year) John Day, Oregon

25 bed Critical Access Hospital. 275 employees

Oversee all nursing services, ancillary services and clinical operations. Serve as Executive team member. Served as Interim CEO during the search for a new CEO.

North Canyon Medical Center 5 years 9 months

Executive team member

Chief Nursing Officer CNO April 2011 - May 2015 (4 years 2 months) Gooding, Idaho

Oversaw all clinical inpatient, outpatient and specialty services at North Canyon Medical Center. Oversaw Quality and Performance Improvement.

Infection Prevention/ Quality Assurance/ Employee Health September 2009 - February 2013 (3 years 6 months) Gooding, Idaho

- -Planned, organized and implemented a comprehensive infection prevention program.
- -Consultant for physicians, nursing and administration in infectious disease, surveillance and outbreak investigation of infectious disease processes.
- -Consultant and planner for hospital emergency preparedness/incident command systems. Collaborate with county and state emergency planning and coordination of services.
- -Developed policies and procedures for infection prevention, employee health, quality assurance, performance improvement and emergency preparedness/incident command programs.
- -Implemented and managed an extensive employee health program.
- -Collaboration with laboratory in the identification and reporting of infectious and reportable diseases to South Central Public Health District, and the State of Idaho.
- -Report to Performance Improvement board on quality issues and current performance improvement projects.
- -Coordinated a free wellness clinic (Mustard Tree) for the under-insured and uninsured to address alternative care options for the community.

 (Open)1 project

South Central Public Health
Nurse Epidemiologist/ Sr. Nurse Manager
March 2000 - September 2009 (9 years 7 months)

Twin Falls, Idaho

- -Developed and implemented public health policies and analyzed their impact and effectiveness for the public.
- -I was responsible for interpreting contracts, budgeting and meeting contract deliverables, as well as writing policies and procedures.

- -Conducted investigations of reportable diseases to protect the public and track outbreaks of infectious disease.
- -Collaborated with and attended infection control meetings in the various hospitals.
- -Distributed disease educational information through television, radio and newspaper.
- -Developed a Tuberculosis (TB) Program and TB clinics for 8 counties in the district.
- -Instructed courses in Tuberculosis, Bioterrorism, and Forensic Epidemiology to Law Enforcement and 2nd year nursing students at the College of Southern Idaho (CSI).
- -Managed a Refugee Program and clinics in collaboration with the College of Southern Idaho's refugee center.
- -Implemented the West Nile Program, including surveillance and trapping of mosquitoes in the advance of West Nile Disease into Idaho.
- -I was responsible for Child Health programs, including immunizations, case management of medically fragile children, Infant Toddler program and Child Safety.

(Open)1 project

St. Bendicts Family Medical Center Laboratory Technician June 1982 - April 2007 (24 years 11 months) Jerome, Idaho

-Generalist in all areas of the laboratory; hematology, immunology, urology, virology, chemistry, microbiology, blood banking, etc.

Full time from 1988 - 2000. Part Time from 2000 - 2007.

St. Benedicts Family Medical Center Staff RN

May 1997 - August 2000 (3 years 4 months)

Jerome, Idaho

Part Time RN - Med Surge,, ER and Urgent Care Clinics

Education

Aspen University

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Masters of Business Administration \cdot (2007 - 2011)

Idaho State University
Bachelor's Degree, BSN · (2005 - 2006)

College of Southern Idaho Associate's Degree, Nursing RN · (1993 - 1997)

Brigham Young University

Non-Professional General Legal Studies (Undergraduate) · (1974 - 1976)